My name's Conan Edogawa!
Meu nome é Conan Edogawa!
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
Shinichi, do ensino médio,
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
Mesmo pequeno, minha inteligência continua genial!
Today's case takes place in a haunted house!
O caso de hoje é numa casa mal-assombrada.
Even if it's hidden in an eerie basement, there's always only one truth!
Mesmo escondida num porão sombrio, a verdade é sempre única!
The first end of the century in 100 years
O primeiro fim de século em cem anos
When told to cry, I laughed instead
Quando me mandaram chorar, eu ri
The first end of the century in a long, long time
O primeiro fim do século em muito, muito tempo
We're leaping into a wide open world
Estamos saltando rumo a um mundo aberto
The things I tried to understand as a child
As coisas que eu tentava entender quando era criança
remain a mystery even as an adult
Continuam um mistério para mim como adulto
I'm neither a hotshot nor especially great
Não sou um figurão nem grande coisa
All I understand is the pounding of my heart
Eu só entendo as batidas do meu coração
It's neither an answer nor the truth
Não é uma resposta, tampouco a verdade
All I have faith in is the pounding of my heart
Eu só acredito nas batidas do meu coração
That and nothing else
E nada mais
Come ghost hunting with us, Conan-kun!
Venha caçar fantasmas com a gente, Conan!
Ghost hunting?
Caçar fantasmas?
Forget about him, Ayumi!
Esqueça, Ayumi!
Conan wouldn't be any help even if he did come!
O Conan não ajudaria mesmo que viesse!
But if it's just you and me who go...
Mas se formos só você e eu...
Where are these ghosts, anyway?
Onde estão esses fantasmas, afinal?
An old mansion over on 4th Street!
Numa velha mansão no 4º distrito!
4th Street?
4º distrito?
Yeah!
Isso!
People call it a horror mansion
Chamam de mansão do horror,
because a man was beaten to death there 5 years ago!
porque há cinco anos um homem foi espancado até a morte lá!
Come to think of it,
Pensando bem,
I do remember a mysterious incident occurring there...
eu lembro de um relato de um incidente assim...
They say that after his wife and son moved out,
Dizem que depois que a esposa e o filho se mudaram,
evil spirits took up residence in the house!
espíritos do mal tomaram conta da casa!
Evil spirits?
Espíritos do mal?
Late at night, people've heard horrible moaning coming from inside,
Na calada da noite, pessoas ouvem gemidos horríveis de dentro,
stray dogs that wander inside are found as skeletons the next day,
cães de rua que entram lá são achados só como ossos no dia seguinte
and then last night, I saw a spirit ball in one of the windows!
e, ontem à noite, eu vi um espírito de fogo numa das janelas!
Well? Doesn't it make you excited?!
E então? Bateu uma curiosidade?
That's nothing but nonsense.
Quanta besteira.
In this scientific day and age, ghosts and monsters should be left
Estamos na era da ciência! Fantasmas e monstros se limitam
to television and comic books.
a TV e quadrinhos.
What? Are you calling Ayumi a liar?!
O quê? Está dizendo que a Ayumi está mentindo?
No, I'm just--
Não, é que...
Then come with us and prove that there aren't any ghosts!
Então venha com a gente e prove que os fantasmas não existem!
After all, you shouldn't be scared one bit!
Afinal, você não deve se assustar!
Eh? Me, come with you?
Hein? Eu, ir com vocês?
You believe me, don't you, Conan-kun?
Você acredita em mim, não é mesmo, Conan?
Don't you?!
Não é?!
Yeah...
Sim.
Okay, then!
Então já é!
Let's get ourselves ready and then beat up some ghosts!
Vamos nos preparar pra detonar uns fantasmas!
Yeah!
Isso!
Are they being serious?!
Sério?
Let's all look at what we brought!
Vamos dar uma olhada no que trouxemos!
I brought a metal ghost-hunting bat!
Eu trouxe um taco de metal antifantasma!
I brought snacks for when we're hungry!
Eu trouxe lanchinho pra quando bater a fome!
I brought flashlights for everyone and a compass so we don't get lost.
Eu trouxe lanternas para todos e uma bússola,
How about you, Conan-kun?
E você, Conan?
I didn't really bring anything...
Eu não trouxe nada...
It's your own fault if you die!
Se você morrer, a culpa é sua!
Yeah! You'll get killed if you're careless!
É! Se for descuidado assim, vai acabar morrendo!
I'll try hard not to die...
Vou tentar não morrer muito...
Do these guys think they're entering a devil's castle or something?
Eles acham que estão no castelo do chefão por acaso?
Hey, this gate won't open...
Ei, o portão não abre...
Don't worry.
Não se preocupe.
I found a secret entrance when I scouted out the place earlier!
Eu achei uma entrada secreta quando estava dando uma olhada mais cedo!
A secret entrance?
Entrada secreta?
Hey! Here it is!
Ei, aqui está!
It's hidden by the grass,
Está escondida pela grama,
but it's just big enough for someone to go through! See?
mas é grande o bastante pra entrar! Viram?
Amazing, Genta-kun!
Incrível, Genta!
A secret entrance...
Uma entrada secreta...
Conan-kun! Hurry up!
Conan, depressa!
Right...
Certo.
It's open!
Está aberto!
It's too dark to see anything...
Está escuro demais para ver qualquer coisa...
It certainly is creepy...
É bem medonho...
Hey... maybe we should go home...
Ei, talvez seja melhor a gente ir embora...
See, it's even starting to rain...
Olha, está até começando a chover...
Don't be stupid! We didn't come this far for nothing!
Não diga besteira! Não chegamos tão longe para nada!
You can go home by yourself if you want!
Se quiser ir embora, pode ir sozinha!
You can't be serious!
Nem pensar!
Lightning!
Raios!
Ayumi!
Ayumi!
Look closer! It's just a sculpture of a demon!
Veja bem! É só a estátua de um demônio!
Aw, man! All I did was fall, but now my arms and legs are all dirty!
Ah, cara! Eu caí e agora estou toda suja!
Nobody's been here for a long time, so the floor's covered with dust...
Faz tempo que ninguém passa aqui,
Here's a washroom!
Um banheiro!
Lucky!
Que sorte!
Walking around with you guys like this,
Andar com vocês aqui
it's almost like we're in a role-playing game!
é quase como brincar de RPG!
Yeah! We're in a party!
Isso, somos um grupo de heróis!
I'm a brave fighter, of course!
Eu sou o guerreiro corajoso, é claro!
I'm a cute girl warrior!
Eu sou uma guerreira fofa!
I'm a gifted magician!
Eu sou um feiticeiro talentoso!
I guess I'm a--
Então acho que eu sou...
You're a villager!
Você é um aldeão!
But villagers aren't party members!
Mas aldeões não entram no grupo!
But you're an important character-- you give us information!
Mas você é um personagem importante que nos dá informações!
Yeah! It's the perfect role for you!
Isso! É um papel perfeito pra você!
Bah! Don't patronize me!
Credo, não me joguem pra escanteio assim!
What's the deal, you guys? Hiding behind the villager, are you?
O que deu em vocês? Estão se escondendo atrás do aldeão, é?
Get moving, villager!
Anda, aldeão!
Conan-kun! You can do it!
Conan, você consegue!
I see. The door opened by itself because of the wind.
Entendi. A porta abriu sozinha por causa do vento.
This is what most "ghosts" turn out to be.
A maior partes dos "fantasmas" é só isso mesmo.
You almost sound like a detective, Mitsuhiko-kun!
Você fala que nem um detetive, Mitsuhiko!
You guys wait here-- I need to use the restroom.
Esperem aqui. Tenho que usar o banheiro.
Will you be alright by yourself?
Você vai ficar bem sozinho?
Of course! I have science and logic on my side!
É claro! Estou do lado da lógica e da ciência!
Man, this house sure is huge!
Cara, que casa enorme!
A really rich person must've lived here!
Uma pessoa muito rica deve morar aqui!
Ghosts can't possibly exist in this scientific day and age!
Não tem como fantasmas existirem nesta era de ciência!
That was probably the sound of wind blowing through a small hole
Deve ter sido o barulho do vento soprando por um buraco pequeno
or something...
ou coisa do tipo.
Alright! I'll check for myself!
Certo, eu mesmo vou conferir!
These stairs go into the basement...
Essas escadas levam ao porão...
Those sounds are coming from down there...
Os barulhos estão vindo lá de baixo...
Alright, then...
Muito bem, então...
Mitsuhiko-kun's taking a long time...
Como o Mitsuhiko está demorando...
It's been twenty minutes...
Já se passaram 20 minutos...
Maybe he's going Number 2!
Talvez seja um número dois!
The sound's getting louder...
O barulho está ficando mais alto...
It's coming from that room!
Está vindo daquela sala!
That was Mitsuhiko's voice!
Era a voz do Mitsuhiko!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Espere, Conan!
There really is something in this mansion!
Tem realmente alguma coisa nesta mansão!
Hey, Mitsuhiko! Where are you?!
Mitsuhiko, cadê você?
Say something! Mitsuhiko-kun!
Diga alguma coisa, Mitsuhiko!
Hey!
Ei!
Where could he have gone?!
Aonde ele foi parar?
He wasn't in the bathroom, either...
Ele também não estava no banheiro...
That scream was no joke!
Foi um grito e tanto!
Something must've happened to Mitsuhiko!
Alguma coisa deve ter acontecido com ele!
Alright, then...
Muito bem, então...
You two hide in a nearby room!
Vocês dois se escondam num quarto próximo!
I'm going to look for Mitsuhiko!
Eu vou procurar o Mitsuhiko!
Listen to me! Don't leave the room, no matter what!
Não saiam de lá, aconteça o que acontecer!
Hey! Conan!
Ei, Conan!
Conan-kun!
Conan!
Something's not right!
Isso é estranho!
Supposedly no one's lived here ever since the murder,
Dizem que ninguém mora aqui desde o assassinato,
so why isn't the water turned off?!
então por que não desligaram a água?
There's also that room with the open window!
E aquele quarto com a janela aberta!
The room hadn't been damaged by wind or rain at all!
Não havia sinal de danos pelo vento ou pela chuva!
That means the window must've been opened fairly recently!
Ou seja, a janela deve ter sido aberta há pouco tempo!
And then there's that secret entrance that was built out of plain view!
E a entrada secreta, que foi construída para ficar escondida!
Someone's been coming into and leaving this mansion!
Alguém anda entrando e saindo da mansão!
But who?!
Mas quem?
And what for?!
E por quê?
Our moms must be worrying about us right about now...
Nossas mães devem estar preocupadas com a gente...
It's already night outside...
Já anoiteceu...
Conan sure is taking a long time...
Como o Conan está demorando...
These aren't for you!
Não são para você!
Mitsuhiko-kun is probably lost and hungry!
O Mitsuhiko deve estar perdido e com fome!
Conan-kun too...
O Conan também...
These are for them! You can't have them!
São para eles! Você não pode pegar!
Fine...
Tudo bem.
I smell food!
Estou sentindo cheiro de comida!
It's coming from down there...
Está vindo lá do fundo...
I'm gonna check it out!
Vou dar uma olhada!
No! Conan-kun said not to leave!
Não! O Conan disse pra gente não sair!
I'll be right back!
Já volto!
Genta-kun!
Genta!
That's strange! There're no signs of anybody anywhere!
Que estranho! Não há indício de ninguém aqui!
Maybe there's really nobody here?!
Talvez não tenha ninguém mesmo?
A photograph...
Uma foto...
Is this the mansion's owner who was killed 5 years ago?
É o dono da mansão, morto há cinco anos?
And is that his wife and son behind him?
E atrás dele é a esposa e o filho?
I thought that the killer was never caught,
Achei que o assassino nunca tinha sido pego
and that the remaining family members moved away...
e que os demais integrantes da família tinham se mudado...
That was Genta's voice!
Era a voz do Genta!
Dammit! I told him to hide!
Droga! Eu disse para ele ficar escondido!
Genta-kun? What's the matter? Did something happen?
Genta, o que foi? Aconteceu alguma coisa?
Genta-kun! Stop trying to scare me!
Genta, pare de tentar me assustar!
Wait! Those aren't Genta-kun's footsteps!
Espere! Não são os passos do Genta!
Then whose are they?!
Então de quem são?
Conan-kun!
Conan!
Don't make any sounds!
Não faça um piu!
Here they come!
Está vindo.
It's a ghost!
É um fantasma!
No, look closer! It's a person!
Não, veja bem! É uma pessoa!
They're just taking something somewhere!
E ela está levando alguma coisa!
But where to?!
Mas para onde?
Wait, Conan-kun!
Espere, Conan!
They're gone!
Sumiu!
There aren't any rooms around here,
Não tem muitos quartos...
...and straight ahead is a dead-end!
...e logo à frente é um beco sem saída!
So where did that person disappear to?!
Para onde ela foi?
I told you it was a ghost!
Eu disse que era um fantasma!
The dust on the floor has a line in it!
A poeira no chão está marcada!
Wait a second! Maybe this is a--
Espere um pouco! Talvez seja...
There's a door here.
Tem uma porta aqui.
Yeah! That person just now went down through it!
Isso! Aquele cara desceu por ela!
No good! It's too much for a kid to open!
Essa não! É pesada demais para uma criança abrir!
I know!
Já sei.
I call these Retractable Suspenders.
São suspensórios retráteis!
One push of a button and they retract from their stretched-out state.
Basta apertar um botão que eles voltam do estado esticado.
They should work great for tying up criminals!
Deve ser ótimo para amarrar bandidos!
Yeah! I'll try using these!
Isso, vou tentar usar!
What are you going to do with them?
O que você vai fazer com isso?
Just watch and see!
Só fique vendo!
Awesome!
Incrível!
A staircase to the basement!
São escadas pro porão!
Maybe Mitsuhiko and Genta are down here!
Talvez o Mitsuhiko e o Genta estejam lá embaixo!
I see light!
Estou vendo uma luz!
A prison cell!
Uma cela de prisão!
What's it doing here?!
Por que tem uma aqui?
There's someone in there! Look, on the bed!
Tem alguém dentro! Veja, na cama!
Who is this guy?!
Quem é esse cara?
Someone's coming!
Tem alguém vindo!
Another bad dream?
Outro pesadelo?
You poor thing...
Pobre coitado...
But that was over 5 years ago-- forget about it already!
Mas foi há mais de cinco anos. Esqueça logo!
No matter how much you suffer, it still won't bring him back to life...
Por mais que você sofra, ele não voltará à vida...
Back to life?!
Voltar à vida?
Could she be referring to the murdered owner of this house?!
Será que ela está falando do dono da casa, que foi assassinado?
If so, then these two people are--
Então, esses dois são...
Eat up.
Coma.
I'm not keeping you locked up down here to make you suffer, you know!
Não estou mantendo você aqui para você sofrer!
Akio! I'm doing this so that you'll have a future!
Akio! É para que você tenha um futuro!
Aha, now I see the truth behind this mansion and that murder!
Isso, agora entendi a verdade por trás desta mansão e do assassinato!
It sounds like we have some more rats that snuck in with the other two...
Parece que tem mais ratos que entraram com os outros dois...
Show yourself. There's no point in hiding!
Apareça. Não adianta se esconder!
Come out!
Saia!
No point in hiding...
Não adianta se esconder...
You're the one who should come out of hiding, ma'am!
Você que devia parar de se esconder, senhora!
I found it in the study earlier...
Eu achei no escritório ainda agora...
The photograph of you and this house's owner,
Uma foto com você e o dono da casa
who was murdered 5 years ago.
que foi morto há cinco anos.
His appearance has drastically changed in the 5 years he's lived down here,
A aparência dele mudou drasticamente
the man in that prison cell!
é o seu filho, o homem na cela!
The mole below his eye was the only thing that couldn't change.
A pinta debaixo do olho foi a única coisa que não mudou.
I thought something was strange when I first entered the house.
Achei que tinha algo estranho quando entrei na casa.
The family moved out so the mansion should've been empty,
A família saiu da casa, então ela devia estar vazia,
but there was still running water.
mas ainda tem água.
After all, nobody is so frivolous as to continually pay the water bill
Afinal, ninguém continuaria pagando a água
And then there's that discretely placed entrance.
E tem a entrada discreta.
Compared to the age of the surrounding walls,
Comparado com a idade das paredes ao redor,
that wooden door was still new.
a porta de madeira é relativamente nova.
My guess is that it was built after the incident...
Eu diria que ela foi feita depois do incidente...
...so that you could enter and leave the mansion without being seen.
...para que você pudesse entrar e sair da mansão sem ser vista.
But as for why it was necessary to make the place look uninhabited,
Mas não sabia por que você precisaria fazer
and why you needed to keep your son locked up in the basement...
nem por que manteve seu filho preso no porão.
...those questions were answered by your conversation just now!
Mas sua conversa de agora respondeu tudo!
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
Conan Edogawa, um detetive.
A detective?!
Detetive?
There are two possibilities that I can think of.
Consigo pensar em duas possibilidades.
The first is that the house's owner was killed by you, his wife,
A primeira é que foi você, a esposa, que matou o dono da casa,
and that you locked your son up because he witnessed the murder.
e trancou seu filho porque ele testemunhou o assassinato.
The second possibility is that it was your son who killed your husband!
A segunda possibilidade é que o seu filho tenha matado o seu marido!
Knowing that he was the killer,
Sabendo que ele era o assassino,
you decided to protect your son by hiding the truth behind the murder.
você decidiu proteger seu filho
But the weight of what he had done was too much for him.
Mas o peso do que ele fez era demais para ele.
The moans coming from this mansion were probably his deranged screams.
Os gemidos vindos da mansão
Your son probably wanted to turn himself in to atone for his crime.
Seu filho queria se entregar para se redimir pelo crime.
But you couldn't allow that to happen.
Mas você não podia deixar que isso acontecesse.
Try to understand! This is all for your sake!
Tente entender! É tudo por você!
Yes. You didn't want your son to be known as a criminal,
Sim, você não queria que seu filho fosse fichado como criminoso,
so you chose to keep him concealed here in absolute confinement.
então você o manteve escondido, em confinamento.
Judging from your conversation just now and from your reaction,
A julgar pela sua conversa e pela sua reação,
your husband's killer must have been--
o assassino do seu marido deve ter sido...
Shut up!
Cala a boca!
Stop!
Pare!
Stop, Mom! He's exactly right!
Pare com isso, mãe! Ele está certo!
That's right! I was the one who killed Dad!
Isso mesmo! Eu matei meu pai!
Akio!
Akio!
It happened on a spring night 5 years ago...
Foi numa noite de março há cinco anos...
I had just failed my third college entrance exam...
Saiu o resultado do vestibular, e eu não tinha passado...
What? You failed another one?!
O quê? Não passou de novo?
You're an embarrassment to your family!
Você é uma vergonha pra família!
You're pathetic! You're a waste of a person!
Você é ridículo! Um desperdício de oxigênio!
I was already very mentally anguished,
Eu já estava bastante angustiado,
so when I heard those words come from my father...
então quando ouvi essas palavras do meu pai...
...I lost control of myself for a split second!
...perdi o controle por uma fração de segundo!
Akio!
Akio!
When I came to, I was holding a blood-smeared candlestick in my hands,
Quando dei por mim,
and my father was lying there on the floor, nearly unrecognizable!
e meu pai estava no chão, quase irreconhecível!
Don't you worry! I'll protect you!
Não se preocupe! Vou te proteger!
Mom!
Mãe!
The rest was just as you said.
O resto foi como você disse.
My mom made it look like a robber killed him
Minha mãe fez parecer que um ladrão o matou
and then she stuck me in this cell.
e me enfiou nesta cela.
But I can't stand it any longer! I can't live like this anymore,
Mas eu não aguento mais! Não posso mais viver assim,
constantly haunted by the murder of my own father!
sempre assombrado pelo assassinato do meu próprio pai!
I want to confess my crime so I can live with myself!
Quero confessar para achar a minha paz!
Get a hold of yourself, Akio!
Recomponha-se, Akio!
Hang in there until the statute of limitations runs out!
Aguente firme até que o crime prescreva!
If we keep quiet, nobody will ever know!
Se ficarmos quietos, ninguém vai ficar sabendo!
Yes, if you remain in hiding like this, you will be able to escape the police.
Sim, se você continuar se escondendo assim, vai poder fugir da polícia.
But you'll never escape from the guilt!
Mas nunca vai fugir da culpa!
Ma'am.
Senhora.
Do you intend to keep this heavy weight on your son
Pretende pôr esse peso nos ombros do seu filho
for the rest of his life?
pelo resto da vida dele?
The night of terror came to an end,
A noite de terror acabou,
and bright sunlight lit up the mansion.
e o brilho do sol iluminou a mansão.
The two who disappeared during the night
Os dois que sumiram durante a noite estavam dormindo no gramado lá fora.
Apparently the woman had put them to sleep with an anesthetic
Parece que a mulher os pôs para dormir com um anestésico
and threw them out of the house.
e os jogou pra fora da casa.
That same day, the son and wife turned themselves in to the authorities,
No mesmo dia, o filho e a esposa se entregaram pra policia,
and a baffling murder case came to an end after 5 long years.
e um caso perturbador de assassinato
Naturally, the four of us were scolded by the grownups...
Claro que nós quatro levamos uma baita bronca...
I sure wish I was back in my normal body.
Como eu queria estar de volta no meu corpo normal.
Just my imagination
Só impressão minha
Playing with threads around my finger while drinking lukewarm tea
Brincando com fios entre os dedos bebendo chá morno
Let's walk lightly to the bossa nova rhythm
Vamos caminhar levianamente ao ritmo da bossa nova
The puzzle pieces are in my hands
As peças de quebra-cabeça em minhas mãos
That's right...
Isso mesmo...
I was in the same place last week but with different clothes
Semana passada eu estava no mesmo lugar, mas com roupas diferentes
Step by step, there's no reason to be anxious
Passo a passo, não tem por que ficar ansioso
Case by case, I don't care if you laugh
Caso a caso, tudo bem se você rir
Beyond the countless days, she's waiting for me
Além dos dias incontáveis, ela espera por mim
I gotta go my own way
Tenho que seguir meu próprio caminho
Another haunted house?!
Outra casa mal-assombrada?
Yeah! Ayumi found another one!
É! A Ayumi achou outra!
This one's on 2nd Street, and it belonged to the Eto family!
Esta é no 2º distrito e era da família Eto.
Eto?
Eto?
People living in the area say it's a spooky mansion filled with weird books,
As pessoas da vizinhança dizem
and a boy who used to live there by himself was eaten by some monsters!
e um menino que morava lá sozinho foi comido por monstros!
A boy who lived by himself in a spooky mansion filled with books?
Um garoto que morava sozinho numa mansão medonha repleta de livros?
2nd Street? Eto?
Segundo distrito? Eto?
Say, are you sure the name was Eto?
Ei, tem certeza de que o nome é Eto?
Yeah! You write it with a katakana "E" and a kanji "TO"!
Sim! É "e" em katakana e "to" em kanji!
Okay! Let's get ready to beat up some more ghosts!
Certo! Vamos detonar uns fantasmas!
Wait! That's not "Eto"! That's "Kudo"!
Espere, não é "Eto"! É "Kudo"!
That's my house!
É a minha casa!
Let's go, villager!
Vamos, aldeão!
He's dead!
Está morto!
We need to contact the police!
Temos que chamar a polícia!
This is the knife they used during filming!
É a faca que usaram durante a gravação!
Which means the killer was someone on the staff!
Ou seja, o assassino era da equipe!
That's it!
É isso!
Now I know the truth behind this incident!
Agora sei quem está por trás do incidente!
On the next Conan--
No próximo episódio de Conan...
Next Conan's Hint:
Dica do próximo Conan:
Fu dog.
Komainu.
Next episode is even more entertaining than a drama.
O próximo é melhor que novela!
No way!
Não pode ser.